<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Swear of the Month</title>
 <link href="http://getpoole.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://getpoole.com/"/>
 <updated>2019-02-03T15:57:29-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://getpoole.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Cory O'Brien</name>
   <email>cory@swearofthemonth.club</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Meat Words</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2019/01/01/meatwords/"/>
   <updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2019/01/01/meatwords</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The holidays have come and gone, but food is still on my mind – how delicious it is, how fraught, but most importantly, how sweary. For whatever reason, it seems that almost every commonly consumed meat is also some kind of swear. Don’t believe me? That’s stupid. Look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beef – as in “to beef with,” or “who beefed?”
Chicken – as in “what are you, chicken?”
Turkey – as in “jive turkey”
Pork – as in “I’d pork her.”
Fish – as in “bargain busted basic fish.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the word “meat” is dripping with euphemistic potential. This can’t be a coincidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why is English like this? Possibly because of all the weighty and carnal connotations of “flesh”, generally. Meat words automatically objectify flesh, by turning it into an inert object meant to be consumed. And since we’ve all got a lot of feelings about our fragile, quivering meat prisons, words that objectify flesh automatically pack a punch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you possess this forbidden knowledge, the world is your prairie oyster. Spice things up by calling someone a turd-ducken or – if you crave a meatless option – a to-fool. Go nuts. Or better yet, go hog-wild. And if anybody finds a sweary use for “venison,” let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>bojo</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/12/01/bojo/"/>
   <updated>2018-12-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/12/01/bojo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month’s swear is stolen from the future - specifically, Back to the Future 2. Since the movie takes place in 2016, and every other chilling prediction it makes has come true, we should long since have been using this swear in our daily conversation. Well, two years late is better than never, so feast your eyes on this beauty:
bojo (noun)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some kind of absolute god damn idiot who doesn’t even know how a hoverboard works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of things are disappointing about the future - hoverboards don’t actually hover, Biff is actually Donald Trump, and we are all doomed to boil alive inside our own atmosphere. But at the very least, we can take some solace in this pleasing swear. But because we have stolen this swear, as it were, through time travel, one great challenge remains: we must invent an origin for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it, as some say, a contraction of “bone jockey”? Or is it a contraction of Boris Johnson’s name? Did a celebrity get too drunk once and try to say “bozo”? Or is it the sound of someone trying to say “blowjob” while simultaneously performing a blowjob? The choice is yours, my little bojos!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lying</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/11/01/lying/"/>
   <updated>2018-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/11/01/lying</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the US Midterm Elections coming up on Tuesday, I figure now is a good time to talk about lying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lying is bad. We know it’s bad, in part, because the words that we have for referring to liars are not good words. “Liar”, for example, is not a word anyone wants applied to them. But it does not stop there, my friends. Lie too much, and the very anatomy of your face may be called into question. You might be labeled “two-faced,” or “mealy-mouthed.” You might be accused of “talking out of both sides of your mouth,” or of having a “nose longer than a telephone wire.” Such a nose would be unsustainable. You do not want a nose of that length attached to your face, my friends. It would be a medical disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progressing beyond mere facial disfigurement, we arrive in the realm of the creatively scatological. A liar might playfully be termed a “bullshitter,” or – less playfully – accused of being “full of shit.” I have, from time to time, accused a dishonest scoundrel of attempting to piss or shit in my ears – an extremely rude and unsanitary activity. But when a lie is particularly brazen and malicious, only one admonition will suffice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t piss on me and tell me it’s raining.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That one phrase paints quite a picture, doesn’t it? Urine, dispensed from a great height, presumably by someone with other convenient piss receptacles available to him. And when the pee-soaked masses complain, the scoundrel attempts to pass it off as a mere meteorological phenomenon! Is there a more potent metaphor for our current political climate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, I have a confession to make: I set out today to come up with a better swear to use on liars, because our current swears don’t seem to be working very well. And I tried, friends. I really did. But the problem is that a swear is only as powerful as the cultural taboo associated with it, and right now … our culture doesn’t seem to agree that lying is a bad thing to do. In ancient Persia, liars used to be punished with death. Now they’re punished with … high political office? I can’t believe I’m saying this, but at this moment, in 2018, swearing alone is not enough to solve this problem. We have to make lying bad again, so that calling someone a “liar”, or pointing out the unusually high temperature of their pants, will once more be the dire insult it deserves to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this Tuesday, don’t just swear with your mouths and typing fingers. Swear with your ballots. Vote the liars out. Maybe then they’ll stop showering us with their mendacious piss.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>thicc</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/10/01/thicc/"/>
   <updated>2018-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/10/01/thicc</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HEY: The thing I’m about to talk about originated in the black community, in AAVE, and was later co-opted by others. I’m going to analyze it, because I think it’s interesting, but this isn’t something I invented. I just think if we’re going to be using this, we should understand what it means and where it came from.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my hobbies is attempting to pronounce things I see on the internet out loud. “Lol”, “fffffff”, and “upside down sad face emoji” have all posed unique challenges – but there is a purpose to this exercise beyond mere amusement.&lt;!--more--&gt; The odd ways we spell and phrase things online aren’t accidents. They’re attempts to make up for the paucity of nuance available in written communication. Mixing some 1’s in with your exclamation points conveys reckless excitement. Omitting a period at the end of a sentence conveys a careless coolness. But over the past few months I have noticed a relatively new construction that merits further study. I call it “the sexual c.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have not seen someone or something described as “thicc” yet, then I don’t know how you’re reading this because you clearly do not have the internet. For the uninitiated, however, “thicc” is a positive descriptor usually applied to any particularly bodacious physical assets. The word has expanded beyond its original meaning however, and has since been applied to everything from sandwiches to dog butts with equal relish. No matter the context, the word “thicc” indicates that whatever is being described is so good as to cause some kind of sexual arousal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is only the beginning, however. Other words, such as “snacc” and “succ” have undergone a similar phonetic transformation, with the same results. The question is, why? Why are we taking the k’s out of our words and replacing them with c’s? While I cannot see into the minds of those pioneering linguists who first dared to do it, I have theories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it should be noted that this phonetic transformation only works on words that end in “[vowel]ck.” Attempting to transform a word ending in different consonants would render the result unrecognizable, and attempting the transformation on a word with additional consonants before the “ck” would disrupt the simplicity which gives the sexual c its effect (see below.) Also, simply adding a “c” onto the end of a word that already ends in c (like “epicc”) just looks dumb. Don’t be that guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you remove the “k” at the end of a word and replace it with a “c”, several things happen. First of all, the hardness and finality of the word melts away. “K” is an abrupt, unambiguous sound. “C” is more subtle, changing its pronunciation based on context. Furthermore, while “cc” is a fairly common phoneme in “standard” English, it is never used to end words. When it does appear, in words such as “success” and “access”, it often manifests as the combination of one hard and one soft sound. In other words, such as “occupation”, it is a hard sound closer to how it is pronounced in words like “thicc”. The determining factor is the vowel that follows the “cc”. However, in words that end in “cc”, there is obviously no following vowel, thus creating an ambiguity that may contribute to a sense of anticipation in the reader. This ambiguity, this anticipation, this tension between hardness and softness … well, perhaps you can see for yourself why double c’s might be sexier than a c and a k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more, a “cc” ending is more extensible than a “ck” ending. Because it is symmetrical, it has no clear ending. Even the shape of the letters hints more at continuation than the sharp angles of the “k.” This allows modifications such as “thi c c” and “thicccccccc.” With no explicit phonetic endpoint, the word can theoretically go on for a very long time – another characteristic that might be desirable in a sexual encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you see, the sexual c injects horniness into a modified word by infusing it with some of the characteristics of luxurious, playful, unhurried sex. On a phonological level, the simple substitution of a “k” with a “c” creates an entirely different look, sound, and – dare I say – mouthfeel. Above, I have mentioned several examples of modified words I have seen in the wild, but to close out this essay, allow me to list some constructions I have yet to see, but would very much like to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fucc
licc
dicc
slicc
bacc (as in “bb got bacc”)
sacc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and of course …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cucc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thancs for reading ~~~&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dog-Botherer Redux</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/09/01/dog2/"/>
   <updated>2018-09-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/09/01/dog2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Long-time Swear of the Month Club subscribers may remember my paean to the archaic swear “dog-botherer.” In my previous essay on the word, I described it as a “forever insult.” At the time, I did not realize just how right I was. My intention with that first essay was to revive dog-botherer as a modern swear, but what I failed to notice was that dog-botherer has already been revived. It has merely taken on a more contemporary form.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am referring, of course, to the delightfully illustrative phrase, “fuck the dog” (minced as “screw the pooch.”). As the original meaning of “dog-botherer” is essentially “dogfucker” (a swear which also survives to this day), “fuck the dog” - meaning “to thoroughly cock up a delicate situation” - is very much an heir to the dog-bothering tradition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need not stop at dogfucking, however. As is often the case, the steady march of sweary evolution has given us access to shades of meaning not available in the original epithet. “Fuck the dog” and “screw the pooch” alone have subtly different connotations, but we can do better. If one is flirting with disaster, we might say that they are “fondling the dog.” If one truly and irreparably fucks up, we might say that they “really took the dog in both hands.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, what was once a simple Shakespearean insult has today blossomed into a wonderland of possible expletives. I encourage you to venture forth and explore this brave new world of canine pleasure. Just remember: don’t fuck any actual dogs. I do not endorse it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Splonk</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/08/01/splonk/"/>
   <updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/08/01/splonk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is, of course, my responsibility as a prominent swearologist to use my platform to raise awareness of certain underutilized swears and swear techniques, but from time to time I must allow my ego free rein. Today is just such a time, and so I give you a brand new, piping hot swear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;splonk
[splɒ̈nk]
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;verb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to ejaculate inaccurately, thus dousing the immediate surroundings in unwanted spooge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To utterly cock up an otherwise good thing through clumsiness, impatience, or poor communication.
a. The party was going great until Phil splonked all over everybody’s good time by busting through the wall screaming “THE COPS ARE COMING” because he saw an especially large pigeon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ejaculate, recklessly dispensed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The fully grown product of recklessly dispensed ejaculate.
a. You utter splonk.
b. Aphrodite is technically the original splonk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for subscribing to the Swear of the Month Club. Until next time: eat clum, splonkers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tapioca Suitcase</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/07/01/tapiocasuitcase/"/>
   <updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/07/01/tapiocasuitcase</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;E3 was a couple weeks ago, and while most people were there to scope out hot new games, I was searching for cool new swears. Lo and behold, as the convention center closed on day one of the event, I overheard a beet-red bald man scream into a mobile phone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For the love of Christ, Ted, I don’t want to walk into my bedroom and see you lying there with your tapioca suitcase hanging out!”
&lt;!--more--&gt;
He proceeded to utter a string of more mainstream genital euphemisms: chocolate starfish, purple-helmeted yogurt-thrower, et cetera, but I hardly heard them. I was still overwhelmed by “tapioca suitcase.” From context I had discovered its meaning: the man was talking about a ballsack. And yet, the phrase he had used continued to dazzle me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just … made … no … sense. I mean yes, sperm is sort of like tapioca? And the ballsack is a place to keep sperm, just as a suitcase is, I guess, a place to keep tapioca? But a suitcase is hard-shelled, whereas a ballsack is anything but. Also, opening a suitcase is almost nothing like opening a ballsack. A tapioca suitcase is about as similar to a ballsack as a ziploc bag of hard-boiled eggs is to a uterus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s what makes it so brilliant. The poor fellow on the other end of the phone clearly knew from context that his nuts were the topic of conversation. Our intrepid swearsmith didn’t need to be accurate in his description. He needed to be ludicrous. His choice of words served its true purpose as a swear: to take the conversation out of the realm of mere anatomy and into the domain of what it must have felt like to walk into a room and see those exposed testes. It made them literally larger than life. Also harder and with more structural integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn from this screaming bald man. Don’t threaten to kick a fuckboy in the nuts - Tell him your foot’s got a date with his tapioca suitcase. Don’t tell that lucky fella you’re gonna suck his dick - Tell him you’re gonna help him unpack his tapioca suitcase. Don’t go balls to the wall - put your tapioca suitcase on the table, open it up, and reveal stack upon stack of crisp hundred dollar bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is your suitcase, friends. Fill it with tapioca, and then use it as a metaphor for nuts.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Syllable Count</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/06/01/syllable/"/>
   <updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/06/01/syllable</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the study of morphology, linguists often examine “minimal pairs” – that is, morphemes which are identical in all but one respect. This allows researchers to gauge the purpose and effect of isolated phonemes in a controlled environment. The field of swearology, too, has its minimal pairs, and by examining them, we will today explore how syllable count influences the potency and purpose of a naughty word.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
To begin, let us consider “shit” and “shee-yit.” For the purpose of comparison, let us assume each word is used as an interjection. “Shit” is most appropriately employed as an expression of dismay (eg. “Shit! My house is on fire!” or “Shit! My dick fell off!”). “Shee-yit”, on the other hand, is a more leisurely expression, better suited for surprise or incredulity (eg. “You ate that whole pig all by yourself? Shee-yit.”) The very length of “shee-yit” suggests less urgency than its shorter sibling. It is a word to be mulled over, to roll around in the mouth. It has none of the urgency of a barked monosyllable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further confirmation, we need look no further than the minimal pair “bitch”/“beeyotch”. Whereas “shit” and “sheeyit” are both considered swears, “beeyotch” is employed more often as a minced oath. Given that the primary difference between the two words in the pair is their syllable count, we can see that the length of the word is being intentionally used to dilute its perceived rudeness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can turn to “fuck”/“fucker” for a third example. When used as an epithet (eg. “You fuck!” or “You fucker!”) we once again see a subtle difference in connotation. “Fuck” is more straightforwardly abusive than “fucker,” which carries with it a sort of playful edge. Consider the difference between “You little fucker,” and “You little fuck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, as a general rule, it seems apparent that increasing the syllable count of a given swear reduces its perceived seriousness. As in all areas of linguistics, however, there are counterexamples which complicate our analysis. Certain slurs, for example, use multiple syllables, and these are among the most serious and abusive words in our lexicon. A possible explanation is that – as these words are meant to belittle and dehumanize – their multisyllabic nature actually serves to reinforce the disrespect intended by the user. In other words, I sincerely hope none of you fuckers use this essay as an excuse to scream slurs at people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on a lighter note, we must address the issue of “motherfucker.” Here we have a four-syllable word which can nonetheless be quite serious indeed. However, it is important to note that “motherfucker” is in fact highly situational, and difficult to employ. Many people (myself included) are entirely incapable of utilizing a sincere “motherfucker” in spoken conversation. A skilled swearsman such as Samuel L. Jackson, who has narrowly specialized in the use of “motherfucker,” may be able to engage the word in devastating ways, to be sure. But judging “motherfucker” based on what Mr. Jackson can do with it would be much like judging the capabilities of a pencil based on what John Wick can do with it. Perhaps most tellingly of all, many users of “motherfucker” omit one or more of the word’s syllables, rendering it as “mo’fucker”, “mothafucka”, or a combination of the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, with some notable exceptions, the syllable rule of swear intensity holds. Go forth, my little swearlings, and use this knowledge as irresponsibly as fucking possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Beyond FUBAR</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/05/01/fubar/"/>
   <updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/05/01/fubar</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;English is lousy with acronyms, and the only thing we like more than acronyms … is lexicalizing our acronyms. From LASER, to DARPA, to the U.S.A. P.A.T.R.I.O.T. Act (Seriously, look it up), us English speakers will shove our forearms straight up our own assholes in the quest to turn a bunch of smaller words into one big word.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
No one is better at this than the military. Not only does the military love acronyms, but they also love swearing, and the marriage of swearing and acronyms is a happy one indeed. It is this joyful domestic union which has brought us such masterpieces as SNAFU (Situation Nominal: All Fucked Up), SUSFU (Situation Unchanged: Still Fucked Up), TARFU (Totally And Royally Fucked Up), and – my personal favorite – BOHICA (Bend Over, Here It Comes Again).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lexicalized acronyms are a great vessel for new swears because their meaning is directly encoded in the word itself. And while abbreviations like OMFG and STFU have their uses, only lexicalized acronyms can be seamlessly incorporated into spoken language. Too long has the military had a monopoly on this powerful and versatile swear-form. It’s time for the workers to own the means of swear production. Here’s a few brand new fuckronyms for your perusal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FISOW&lt;/strong&gt; – Fucked In Several Obvious Ways&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LAFLA&lt;/strong&gt; – Looking Amazing, Feeling Like Ass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRIMP&lt;/strong&gt; – Greedy Racist In Management Position&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FWAP&lt;/strong&gt; – Fucked Without A Prayer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOYMAN&lt;/strong&gt; – Shitting Out Your Mouth, Ad Nauseum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALWAES&lt;/strong&gt; – At Least We’re All Equally Shafted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WEGAS&lt;/strong&gt; – Who Even Gives A Shit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and finally,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ORBUS&lt;/strong&gt; – Occasionally Rad, But Usually Shitty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the above as a linguistic aperitif to get your own swear engines rumbling. I look forward to plenty more frankenwords from the lot of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>J*sus Chr*st</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/04/01/jesus/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/04/01/jesus</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Easter. Here’s a list of all the ways I know to say “Jesus Christ” without saying “Jesus” or “Christ”:
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gee whillikers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gee whiz&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeepers creepers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jiminy Christmas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jiminy Cricket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeeze Louise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Judas Priest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jumping Jehosephat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeezy Creezy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jersey Mike’s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cheese and rice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cheese and crepes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jibjab Crumbo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bajeezus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bejabbers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holy Chris&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For crying out loud&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cripes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crikey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fuck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy spring.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Weenie</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/03/01/weenie/"/>
   <updated>2018-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/03/01/weenie</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, a New York publishing house was foolish enough to offer me a book contract. I got a lot out of that deal – money, a bunch of free copies of the book, and a smug sense of superiority to name just a few. But possibly the most valuable thing I gained was an unexpected lesson in swearing. Until that time, I’d only had the readers of my website to answer to, and so I’d mostly used whatever words I felt like using. The editors at the publishing house, however, pointed out some things I hadn’t consciously realized. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, they told me, I was seriously overusing “fuck” instead of making actual jokes. I’ve already written about that, so there’s no need to discuss it further. More importantly, they told me that certain words I’d considered harmless were in fact offensive to potential readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most surprising of these – to me – was “pansy.” Given my privileged background, I hadn’t even considered that the word might have its origins in homophobia. To me, it just meant “wimp.” I actually got mad at the editor who told me I had to stop using “pansy,” because it seemed like such a harmless word to me. Even worse, I had no idea what could replace it. I’d long since given up “pussy,” and  while “wimp” means the same thing, it doesn’t have nearly the bite, and it’s only one syllable. I was at a loss, until a friend opened my eyes to one of the greatest insults of all time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Weenie.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you heard a chorus of angels sing out upon reading that word, then you are a weirdo. No angels sang just now. You are hearing things. But if what you want to do is insult somebody’s gumption, “weenie” is a gift from the gods. It diminishes your target with the help of the “-ie” diminutive suffix, it has two luxurious syllables, and the only thing it makes fun of is penises, which are already pretty funny. In short, “weenie” is everything I thought “pansy” was, just without the history of homophobia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even better, “weenie” comes with a companion word, “wiener”, which is even more useful. Sure, you could call someone a dick, a cock, a tool, a wanker, or a prick but the hard consonants in those words make you sound like you’re trying too hard. A weiner, on the other hand, is a person who is unpleasant in the way that a shitty four-year-old is unpleasant. The current president of the United States, for example, is a wiener. Or a dildo. Dildo works too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it friends: the story of a journey of self-discovery that lead me to discover something outside myself: weenies. So many weenies.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Minced Oaths</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/02/01/minced/"/>
   <updated>2018-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/02/01/minced</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Minced oaths get a bad rap. To self-respecting swearologists, they’re often looked down upon as low-fat, sugar-free swear substitutes. To many of the prudes they’re supposed to placate, even minced oaths are too rude. But to me, an intellectual, minced swears are friggin’ cool as heck, and ruddy interesting to boot. &lt;!--more--&gt;
The low-fat/sugar-free analogy is a bad one, actually. Whereas ersatz foods are designed to be almost indistinguishable from their full-flavored counterparts, minced oaths are specifically constructed to avoid being mistaken for the real deal. Consider “fuck” and its most commonly used alternatives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;frig&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;frick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;freak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fudge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly there are phonological constructions much closer to the original word which we could use instead. But no one says “fub” or “fut”, and “fug” – while sometimes used – is rare. Notice that each of the words listed above has undergone at least two phonetic transformations in order to achieve its minced form. The vowel sounds in every example besides “fudge” have been altered. The ending consonants have often been shifted. Most interestingly, almost every example includes an alveolar approximant (r or l) inserted after the first, most identifiable letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now go look up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=food+spelled+wrong+meme&amp;amp;oq=food+spelled+wrong+meme&quot;&gt;“food spelled wrong meme.”&lt;/a&gt; Notice that the exact same techniques have been used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bettermyths.com/mershed-perderders.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MERSHED PERDERDERS = Mashed Potatoes, with half the vowels shifted, t’s swapped for d’s, and r’s inserted. This is what we do when we want everyone to know we’re spelling something wrong on purpose. It’s also what we do when we want to make absolutely sure that we are pronouncing something incorrectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s look at some of the most common mincings of “damn”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dang&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deng&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that all five have completely removed the “m” which dominates the ending of the original word. Without the “m” the “n” sound changes completely. But we don’t say “Dan” when we’re mad, unless we’re mad at a person named Dan. That’s still not enough of a misspelling. We’ve either got to insert an “r” (there’s that alveolar approximant again), or add a “g” to the end. “Ng” is a reasonably common phoneme in English, but “mg” is basically unheard-of. Nobody’s gonna be mistaking these words for their more-offensive cousin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, that’s the purpose of mincing oaths. It’s not just about technically obeying the rules of polite conversation – about convincing other people that we aren’t saying bad words. It’s also about convincing ourselves that what we’re saying isn’t that bad. Minced oaths allow us to enjoy the cathartic nature of swearing, while stripping the words of any taboo meaning or potential for abuse. Notice that while “aw, fudge” sounds relatively okay, “I want to fudge you on the counter” sounds downright ridiculous. “Gosh darn it” sounds quaint, but “darn you to heck” sounds pretty silly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty more minced oaths in English, and not all of them follow the phonological rules I’ve discussed above. Perhaps one day I’ll create a guide to mincing your own oaths, so that we can invent a whole new class of minced epithets. For now, however, my point is this: minced oaths aren’t low-fat cusses. They’re swears with the safety on. Just as a gun’s safety makes sure we only use it when we really mean to, minced oaths allow us to be intentional about our swear usage. So consider giving a few frigs and freaks instead of fucks, so that when only fucks will do, you still have some left to give.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cuck</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2018/01/01/cuck/"/>
   <updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2018/01/01/cuck</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been online any time in the past year (or if you have your butler print out Reddit every morning so you can read it over coffee) you have probably seen someone call someone else a “cuck.” Cuck has joined (though unfortunately not replaced) words like “fag” and “tard,” in the ever-classier lexicon of the alt-right.&lt;!--more--&gt; Rather than referring to an unchangeable aspect of identity like these other words, however, “cuck” attempts to shame its target by impugning a supposed cornerstone of his masculinity: his ability to not have his wife fucked by other men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuck is actually a contraction of a much older epithet: cuckold. It is derived from the Old French cucu, meaning the cuckoo bird, notorious for laying its eggs in other birds’ nests. Weirdly, it doesn’t refer to the adulterer – who would properly be called a cuckolder – but rather to the “victim” of adultery. A cuckold is always male. If a woman’s partner is sleeping around, she can be called a cuckquean, but the term is much less common. This is probably because (among other reasons) one implicit threat of cuckoldry is being fooled into unwittingly raising another man’s offspring. A woman, for some fairly obvious reasons, would be much harder to fool in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuckolds have been the subject of derision for centuries, and this scorn has largely gone unexamined. But it’s 2018. A toilet is president and the atmosphere is on fire. I say we re-examine our aversion to cuckhood. I say we take it as a compliment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While cuck is originally derived from cuckold, a quick look at urban dictionary shows that it now signifies far more. A cuck is “spineless,” “a little bitch,” someone “who holds leftist views, politically speaking.” All of this, bound up in whether or not a guy’s wife is fucking other people. Seems a bit narrow-minded. What about ethical polyamory? What about guys with stepchildren, or adopted children? What about people who are just super into watching their wives fuck other dudes? Are we so strapped for measures of character that it really all comes down to whether you can build a wall around a pussy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you’re reading this, I doubt I need to convince you that cuck is a silly insult. You may still be skeptical, however, that it’s a compliment. To the skeptics among you, I offer one compelling data point:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;king-arthur-was-a-cuck&quot;&gt;King Arthur was a cuck.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the single greatest king of all time, the dude other British monarchs were consciously emulating for centuries. That dude was the cuckiest cuck who ever cucked. His BEST FRIEND fucked his wife, the QUEEN, over and over again for YEARS and he did nothing until he was absolutely forced to. Why? Because he was spineless? Was the guy who brought law to Britain, founded the Round Table, and pulled a sword out of a god damn stone a little bitch? No. King Arthur let Lancelot fuck his wife for the good of the kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is Lancelot King Arthur’s best bro, he’s also the greatest knight in the world, and a key source of Arthur’s mandate. You may recall that when Arthur finally is forced to punish Lancelot (due to the machinations of his failson Mordred), it leads inevitably to the end of the Round Table. Now, I’m  a way shittier dude than King Arthur, but I want to believe that if I had to choose between sacrificing everything I ever worked for and letting another dude fuck my wife, I’d pick option B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what a cuck really is, my friends: a dude who realizes that some things are more important than not having your wife fucked. I know most cucks aren’t the once and future king of all of England, but even on a more mundane level – is a guy who sticks around to raise the kids some other fuckboy fathered really the guy we want to be mocking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, cuckolds get sweet horns! Unsatisfied with jamming just one animal metaphor into their euphemism for adultery, medieval europeans took to saying that dudes who got cheated on “wore the horns of a cuckold.” Apparently they said this because stags give up their mates when other stags out-horn them. In fact, in Italy and some other places, it’s still considered insulting to throw the horns. Yes, the same horns you throw at a fucking metal concert. Cuck on, dudes. Like, does anyone actually believe that having horns would be anything other than awesome? I don’t care how stubby the horns are. People don’t have horns. Any amount of horn on a person is a bonus. If being a cuck means I can headbutt my way through a car window, someone please fuck my wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, I’m not saying getting cheated on isn’t shitty. That kind of betrayal is always going to suck. But the bad guy in that shitty situation isn’t the person who’s being cheated on. It’s the people doing the cheating. If we all strive to be as kind and understanding as King Arthur in the face of that shittiness, maybe we, too, will some day deserve to call ourselves cucks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The World Fuck Crisis</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2017/12/01/fuckcrisis/"/>
   <updated>2017-12-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2017/12/01/fuckcrisis</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know what you’re here for, friends. You come expecting a fresh new swear to stuff into your language satchels, like giddy trick-or-treaters at the front door of a crotchety uncle. Ordinarily I would oblige. But the purpose of this swear of the month club has long since expanded beyond the mere coining of neologisms. I have made it my mission not only to arm you with new swears, but with the skill to put your arsenal of swears to good use. And so, with a heavy heart, I must inform you of a crisis that threatens the very heart of sweardom: we have reached peak fuck.&lt;!--more--&gt;
It is hard to imagine that a swear which has been with is for so long could possibly lose its edge. In fact, what with our “fuckboys” and “fuckwits,” “fucknuggets” and “clusterfucks,” one might at first  assume that we are currently experiencing a fuck renaissance. But even the most prodigious fucker can fuck too much, my friends, and as a society – if we do not take steps now to conserve our precious fuck supply – we run the risk of finding ourselves all fucked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words wear out with use. We see this most clearly with synonyms for cool. “Epic” is a good recent example of this. “Epic” once referred only to grand deeds and heroic tales. It was a word with power. Because it had power, later generations used it to describe things they felt powerfully about – first historical events and political upheavals, then dramatic victories, then regular victories, then hilarious failures, and then … mealtimes? Today, using the word “epic” in any sense will earn you little more than a sneer. We used the word because it was powerful, but our use depleted its power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true of fuck. While it has long been insulated from this corroding process by the fact that people are less willing to be heard saying it publicly, the proliferation of uncensored language enabled by the internet has lead us to give and receive more fucks than at any other time in history. As quantity increases, potency decreases, and so we find ourselves in a world of diminishing fucks. We live in a world where friends can jovially tell each other to “fuck off,” where “fuck me,” is an expression of mild exasperation, and where many individuals (myself included) use “fucking” as a replacement for “um.” It’s no longer enough to tell a bastard to go fuck himself. We must append additional epithets and adjectives, or at very least an uncomfortable-sounding object with which to do the fucking. As the result of our pathological overfucking, fuck is rapidly becoming a CVS-brand swear. In short, we may have fucked this up for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are at a crossroads, friends. We can decide to preserve our fucks for future generations to enjoy, or we can continue the thoughtless fuckery of the past, until our beloved “fuck” goes the way of “epic.” I know that so far I have played the role of doomsday apostle, but I would not be delivering this bad news if I did not have some good solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we must understand that “fuck” itself is not that fucking funny. This is a truth near and dear to my heart, as I spent five years of my life writing the word “fuck” next to the names of various gods and goddesses. When I ran Myths RETOLD, I would often get emails from fans who attempted to imitate what they thought of as my writing style – constant line breaks, and manifold conjugations of “fuck” inserted in lieu of jokes. What people didn’t seem to realize was how much time I spent figuring out how not to write “fuck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started out, of course, I fucked with abandon. But over time, I realized that I was using the word as a lazy substitute for linguistic precision. The turning point came about when I was working on my first book. The publisher insisted that I dramatically reduce the number of fucks per page. At first I bristled at the request, but in editing out the fucks, I found that I was forced to come up with ever more creative replacements (“a shot glass full of sperm” being a personal favorite).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One theme I’ve attempted to drive home with the swear of the month is that the potency of a swear is directly proportional to its precision. You can call anyone a bastard, but only Donald Trump is a deranged, rotting canteloupe with a big desk and tiny hands. Robbed of its shock value, fuck is a pretty generic swear. As our culture develops a healthier attitude towards sex, fuck will only become less obscene. Thus, if we want to continue to use our fucks, we must use them wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two major ways to effectively use fuck, in my opinion. The first is to create tension between linguistic registers. Fuck may become less offensive, but I doubt it will ever be a part of “formal” English, and so using fuck in conjunction with seemingly unfuckable words will continue to pack a punch for decades to come. Phrases like “fucking pavlovian”, “serene as fuck”, and “exi-fucking-stential” exemplify this technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second method, perhaps more broadly applicable, is to embrace fuck’s status as a generic curse in order to create new swears. Much as a chef adds salt to transform unremarkable vegetables into a meal, we can add “fuck” to transform nearly any innocent word into a vector for abuse. I discussed this briefly a few months ago in my essay on the etymology of “fuckboy,” but the principle bears repeating. If I call you a “yam salesman,” you will probably be left scratching your head. If I call you a “fucking yam salesman,” on the other hand, you will still be confused, but you will at least know that I meant to insult you. A “bell” is merely something that rings, but what is a “fuckbell”? Clearly not something you want to be, I’ll tell you that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this simple technique, we gain access to nigh infinite swear combinations. Suddenly, any word can be a swear – the more innocuous the better. The great task of this decade, I suspect, will be finding the best of these combinations for inclusion in the lexicon. We already have “fuckboy,” but what about “fucklad?” What about “fuckbird”? What about “fucktree”? The decomposing corpse of the once-proud F-word can yield ample fertilizer for our richly offensive imaginations. All it takes is a shift in mindset, from copulation … to conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the fucking circle of fucking life, fuckers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Skinjob</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2017/11/01/skinjob/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2017/11/01/skinjob</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many entertainment properties have their own proprietary swears. Battlestar Galactica has “frack”, Firefly has “gorram,” and so on. Most of these seem to have been invented primarily to get around the censors. There’s another reason swears are invented in fictional worlds, though, and the Bladerunner movies exemplify it: the slurs that exist in a world tell us a lot about the world. Don’t worry, I’m not going to spoil the new Bladerunner for you. All I want to talk about is the word “skinjob.”&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skinjob is a slur used by humans in both movies as a pejorative term for androids (though not, interestingly, by the characters in the book. In the book, androids are referred to as “andys”). It’s a very satisfying word on a morphological level. It evokes words like  “rimjob” and “nutjob” while managing to be even easier to pronounce thanks to the “nj” compound at its center. “Skin” evokes carnality in a way that suggest obscenity without actually using it, thus placating the censors. On top of that, skinjob is an especially ironic epithet because it could just as easily apply to humans as replicants, subtly reinforcing the theme of human/android duality that lies at the center of Bladerunner. This word is doing a lot of work, basically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that “skinjob” exists as a slur tells us a lot about how humans view replicants in this future dystopia. Slurs are a type of language meant to abuse and dehumanize. But replicants, we’re told, are not human. How can you dehumanize something that isn’t human? We don’t have slurs for giraffes or dolphins, and we certainly don’t have slurs for microwaves (unless you count “hunk of junk”). “Skinjob”, then, humanizes replicants in order to dehumanize them. It speaks to the very human tendency to assign human motivations even to things they’re certain aren’t human, and then to immediately hate those things for being too human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More broadly, slurs in fiction tell us which groups are oppressed, and by whom. They make us reflect on the divisions in our own world. What’s more, they provide another level of abuse that powerful, callous characters can inflict on the less powerful. Because, as a rule, the more targeted a swear is, the more personal, the more viscerally offensive it is. That’s why we often attach adjectives to words like “motherfucker” and “asshole”; it’s not that the words themselves aren’t powerful, it’s that they aren’t specific enough. This is the terrible power of slurs – they attempt to reduce a person to some accident of anatomy or culture, and to completely capture that identity inside one word. They are a way of saying, “you are such a foul being that I have invented word just for people like you.” Slurs are a form of evil magic – a spell we all have access to, and should never cast. But we can learn a lot, in fiction, from watching others cast the spell.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Beyond Garbage</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2017/10/01/garbage/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2017/10/01/garbage</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently it has become fashionable to call people, things, and events “garbage.” Within the last few years, we have taken to calling shitty people “garbage people”, and bad television “garbage television.” Garbage isn’t a new pejorative – one might say the recent trend represents a return to vogue rather than a brand new development – and its popularity is understandable. It’s simple, gracefully evades the censors, and has a full, luxurious mouthfeel. I believe, however, that there is another motive for the resurgence of garbage as an insult; a motive that may yield further swears for our collective use. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a world beset with actual garbage. Nuclear waste, agricultural runoff, mill tailings, waste carbon. There is a literal island made of literal trash in the middle of the literal ocean. We are confronted, constantly, with the fact that every moment we spend living and consuming adds to a pile of festering garbage which we will eventually drown in. This anxiety, I think, is part of what makes garbage such an effective swear these days. Garbage is our eventual death sentence. It is what we shit out as a society. Nobody wants to be garbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, slang wears out quickly. Already, garbage has been robbed of its initial sting by overuse. But the principles behind garbage as a swear can yield words to replace it. First, most straightforwardly, we can simply adopt other words for industrial waste. Some options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scrap&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chaff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Waste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refuse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Runoff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smog&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoilage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… As well as the incredibly useful “pink slime.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the grand-daddy of all these terms is the ever popular “slag” - literally waste rock filtered out during the smelting process. In addition to its unbeatable mouthfeel, slag also gives us the compound swear “slag heap”, which illuminates the second principle of waste-based swears: excess is insult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I wrote an article on hole-based suffixes to insults. I said that holes were useful for building compound swears as they could either imply an absence, or a cavity to be filled with a bad thing. I did not, however, address the similar utility of “heap” and other words that imply an abundance. Just for starters, we can concoct such gems as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shitpile&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cocktower&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buttmound&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fuckmountain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clitbarrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… Not to mention -hill, -knoll, -hump, -lump, and -clump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining these two principles, we can see our way to a swearology that casts its victims as nexuses of pollution. We can call an opponent a “festering mound of pink slime,” a “smog-belching chaff-humper”, or “a greasy hog lagoon.” If we truly wish to usher in a new era of conservation, we must work together to make pollution a seriously dirty word. Or, I mean, a collection of seriously dirty words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, I’m just trying to come up with a social justice related reason to call someone a “greasy hog lagoon.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Actually Swearing</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2017/09/01/actually/"/>
   <updated>2017-09-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2017/09/01/actually</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a lot of time talking about “swearing” as a general category. But why is “swearing” a label we use to refer to bad words? In court, one swears to tell the truth. In marriage, one swears to honor and cherish and whatever. When one enters public office, one goes through a “swearing-in” ceremony. And of course we cannot forget about the most sacred type of promise left to us in this age of perfidy: the “pinky-swear.” To swear is to promise in the most sincere and holy of ways, so why is the word also synonymous with “call your dad a shitlord?” Well … because of how sacred those oaths once were, it turns out. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve talked before about the two overarching categories of bad words: obscenity and profanity. Obscenities are words we don’t use because they refer to taboo body parts or functions – fucking, shitting, pissing, farting, tickling the sweaty windsock, etc. Profanity, on the other hand, refers to words that are bad because they violate some high-level social or divine prohibition – god damn, go to hell, holy shit, etc. One might argue that the word “motherfucker” is unique in that it straddles the two categories (phrasing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, most of our bad words are obscenities, not profanity. Scholars like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medievalists.net/2013/11/by-gods-bones-medieval-swear-words/&quot;&gt;Melissa Mohr&lt;/a&gt; argue that this is because of how much privacy we have these days. We have the luxury of shame, in that we don’t have to share a bed with our siblings while they have sex, or poop in the same room as our dads, so we can afford to wall those kinds of words off from polite conversation. The importance of religion in regulating public affairs has also declined in recent times due to things like contract law, riot cops, and the government being run by vampires. Thus, profanity doesn’t pack the punch it used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Medieval Europe, on the other hand, people had very little privacy, so shitting wasn’t such a big deal. But religion was a much bigger deal than it is now, and not just because the church was the biggest single source of education/cool robes. People needed to rely on each other’s word for a lot of things, and that’s where swearing came in. The idea was that when you swore, God actually took note and made sure you kept your end of the deal, so you better not fuck it up. This also meant that if you routinely broke your oaths, or just swore about a bunch of dumb shit all the time for basically no reason, you were essentially wasting God’s time. Not a thing you want to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more, there was this idea going around that people’s words could physically alter the bodies of the dudes up in heaven. This probably came from how Catholic Priests seemed to be able to stuff Christ’s body into a bunch of wine and crackers after every Sunday service, so people figured this was just a thing you could do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you might think that knowing that a certain class of words has the incredible power to not only attract God’s attention, but also physically fuck up His body and the body of His son would make people a little bit afraid to use these words. But it actually just made people want to use those words all the time. It’s the same reason people use words like “fuck” now: when you stub your toe or you’re pissed off at someone or you just saw someone cut off a dude’s head, you want to use the most powerful language available to you. And so we ended up with a catalog of beautiful old-world swears, including “God’s bones,” “God’s balls,” “Christ’s Nails,” “Christ’s blessed heart,” and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, many of these oaths were shortened or minced. We got the ultralight “by God,” which became “By golly,” “by gosh,” “by gum,” and my favorite, “by gad,” because that one just looks like a typo. “Jesus Christ,” became “Jeeze,” and eventually “Jeeze Louise,” and we’ve even incorporated gods from alternate pantheons, as in “By Jove,” and “By Odin’s Beard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn’t until I saw the oath “By Asimov’s Beard” in a recent webcomic that I realized we’ve entered a new era of swears. In this secular era, we are empowered as never before to swear to all kinds of dumb shit. You were probably wondering why I’ve been going on at such length about the history of  oaths, and the answer is this: through my studies I have cracked the code, the underlying formula of this powerful yet distinguished swear-type. Now you too can harness the linguistic power that the Medieval Europeans held in such high regard. Simply arrange your swear thusly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(by)[Subject]’s [object]!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject of your swear must be a proper name, and it must not be a living person. It may be a fictional character, a divine entity, or a deceased person of godlike stature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The object may be literally anything, as long as it might conceivably be possessed by the subject. “Beard” is always acceptable if nothing else is forthcoming. Some examples follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Cthulu’s wings!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Lincoln’s log!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Xena’s blades!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Cleopatra’s beard!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Caesar’s ghost!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Loki’s lung!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Hubbard’s hands!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Juno’s eyes!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Bowie’s bulge!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so on. But I have an ulterior motive here, a higher purpose: phrases like these were once profane because we believed that words had magic meaning, that our promises could have a physical effect on the world around us. When you say these swears, put the full force of your sincerity behind them. Bring that magic back into the world. Bring that magic back into the word, and then keep &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; word. Swear you’ll do it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>You'll Hate These</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2017/08/01/juice/"/>
   <updated>2017-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2017/08/01/juice</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a quick one this month. Here’s three rhyming euphemisms to never say:&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Slap laps – have sex&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bury the cherry – have sex, but for the first time&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Produce the juice – urinate&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m deeply sorry, to you and to humanity at large. This knowledge is perhaps too terrible, too dangerous for mortal minds. As Oppenheimer said upon witnessing the first successful test of the atomic bomb, “I am become death, destroyer of words.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Shit in Milk</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2017/07/01/shitmilk/"/>
   <updated>2017-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2017/07/01/shitmilk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello again, fuckers and fuckees, and welcome to this month’s swear. Today we will be discussing a phrase near and dear to my butt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“To shit in one’s milk.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I grew up with this swear. It practically raised me. So I was shocked to find that many people are unfamiliar with this evocative expression. For those of you as yet uninitiated in the mysteries of shitmilk, let me break it down for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This phrase can take any of several forms. Perhaps the most common is the question: “Who shat in your milk?” ie, “What are you so grumpy about?” You may be more familiar with the derivation, “Who pooped in your breakfast cereal,” which, you may notice, also implies the presence of milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are other ways to combine shit with milk, my friends. One might say, “We’re really shitting in each other’s milk here” (We’re mutually ruining each other’s prospects), “I don’t mean to shit in your milk, but …” (I’m not trying to ruin your day, but …), or even “Wow, I really shat in my own milk there.” (I totally fucked myself over with that boneheaded action.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this swear so good? Because in a few short words, it concocts a cartoonishly unpleasant scenario. To poop in someone’s milk is to invest significant time and effort with the sole purpose of ruining a good thing. (Even if you do not like milk, you will have to admit that milk with shit in it is worse than milk sans shit.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we generalize this swear, rendering it into the form “who [bodily function] in your [consumable]?” We can, but the results will never surpass the original. While “who jizzed in your happy meal?” and “who pissed in your latte?” are both heroic efforts, the magic of the original phrase is tied to the words “shit” and “milk.” Let’s look at each individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike jizz, shit is primarily nonsexual, and though producing both can be pleasurable, pleasure is not the primary purpose of shitting. Thus, shit eliminates potential ulterior motives for adulterating a beverage that might be present if jizz were substituted. At the same time, shit is more vile than piss, blood, or spittle. Puke is a serious contender here, but it falls short in that it is frequently produced involuntarily, whereas to shit into a beverage is almost always a premeditated act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s look at some alternatives to milk. Beer is right out – it lacks milk’s innocence, and as soon as alcohol is involved the realistic possibility of people shitting in all kinds of unlikely receptacles sharply increases. We don’t want to be realistic here, so let’s change “beer” to “root beer.” This is better, but the brown-on-brown motif lessens the shit’s visual impact, and the carbonation somehow makes the shit seem cleaner and more contained. “Orange juice” is even closer to the ideal, but the citric acid and bright color of the juice again run the risk of neutralizing the shit. This leaves us with milk – an opaque white liquid that superficially conceals the shit’s presence while doing nothing to mask its flavor or texture. A beverage suitable for all ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put a lot of thought into this, as you can see, but I am by no means infallible. If you find a substance/beverage combo even more titillating than shit and milk, please share it with me in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of note is the fact that this phrase is almost never used as a threat. “I’ll shit in your milk,” might seem tempting at first, but think of the effort required to follow through on the threat. You’ll have to put yourself in a very compromising position in order to achieve the desired firing angle, exposing yourself to more ridicule than your unlucky target. That’s ignoring the fact that, in response to your warning, your target might simply switch to almond milk preemptively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That concludes this month’s swear discussion. I hope you never have occasion to use this phrase, as it is only applicable when someone has needlessly fucked someone else over, but if such a calamity does transpire, at least you will have the words to swear about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Clum, Twizbit, Shale</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com/2017/06/01/clum/"/>
   <updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2017/06/01/clum</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month we’re taking the swear-of-the month club back to its roots, with three invented swears to add to your arsenal. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;noun&lt;/em&gt;, Literally, a tiny gobbet of gelatinous cum that refuses to be dislodged from skin, clothing, or hair.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ve got a little clum on you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;noun&lt;/em&gt;, Figuratively, a person who invites themselves to social gatherings and stays long after all the desired guests have departed.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Look, Steve, I was trying to be polite, but it’s 3AM. Stop being a clum and go home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt; clummy, clumming, clummily&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;twizbit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;noun, Literally, those tiny, shitty Twizzler bites that aren’t even as good as real Twizzlers, which are already basically just an edible form of red plastic.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve been rationing my Halloween candy, but all I’ve got left is a tube of toothpaste and a bag of twizbits. I think I’ll have some toothpaste.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;noun, Figuratively, a small-minded, miserly substitute for a real person.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I already knew Steve was a real clum, but I didn’t know he was a twizbit until he ordered a steak at dinner and then insisted that we split the check evenly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;noun, Literally, a fine-grained, elastic sedimentary rock composed of mud that is a mix of flakes of clay minerals and tiny fragments (silt-sized particles) of other minerals, especially quarts and calcite&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I didn’t make up the word “shale.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;verb, To flake under the slightest pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I told that clum Steve that the party was a potluck, and he shaled like a twizbit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apologies to anyone named Steve. I’m not talking about Steves in general, just one particular Steve. You know who you are.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
